Hello friends, if your age is between 25 to 50
years, then I ask you a question.
What is the biggest fear in your mind
?  The health of parents means that they should
always remain well.  They should
not have any disease.  Always stay safe.  But the
reality is friends that as
age increases,
diseases start occurring.  And when
a major medical emergency occurs, do you
know what happens first?  All your
savings are gone.  So, first of all let me
show you some numbers that will shock you.
So, as you can see on your screen.
This is the
cost of medical treatment in India.  If you suffer from
any heart disease, it costs around Rs 3
to 5 lakh.  Whereas if liver
treatment or liver transplant has to be done, then the
cost comes to ₹20 to ₹25 lakh.
If parents slip in the bathroom,
hip replacement costs Rs 3 lakh.  Knee
replacement is
common these days.  It costs at least Rs 3 to 5 lakh.
And if God forbid you get cancer, it
costs between ₹5 lakh to ₹15 lakh.   That
means friends, if even a small medical
emergency occurs, it can wipe out lakhs of rupees of your earnings.
But friends, now the question will
arise that what is its solution?  So there is
only one solution to this and that is a solid
health insurance for the parents.  So
friends, in today's video I will
tell you the two best health insurance plans for number one parents.
Number two, what are the must-have
features?
And number three, how much will the premium cost?
That means how much will you have to pay every year?
But friends, before telling you the names of insurance, first of all
I will tell you
what should be there in the insurance so that no
insurance company can scam you.
So the first feature is Avoid Family
Floater Plan.  Friends, what many people do is that they
take a family floater plan.
What this means is that there is only
one insurance for the entire family.  In that, you
also come, your wife also comes, children
also come and along with them senior citizens
i.e. parents also come.  But this
could prove to be your biggest mistake.
Why am I saying this?  Friends, if the age of the parents
is higher then their chances of getting the claim are
also higher.  They
also have a higher chance of getting diseases.  Therefore, their
annual premium is also higher.
So when you take the same plan,
you are paying higher premium for yourself also.
Feature number two low waiting period
for pre existing disease.  That is, suppose the
parents already have some disease.   That
means someone has diabetes, someone has
thyroid or some other major disease.  So what
most insurance companies do is that
in such cases they increase the waiting period so much
that you cannot take the insurance claim for two, three or four years.
So
what is the benefit of such insurance?  Feature number three is
no room rate limit and no sub limit.
Friends, what this means is that what many
insurance companies do is that they say
that you cannot take a room for more than Rs 5000.
If you are admitted in a hospital,
suppose there is an emergency and you have to be
admitted in ICU but the ICU
charge is Rs 20,000 but your insurance
allows a room for only Rs 5000, then
you will have to pay Rs 15,000 from your pocket and the
second thing is the disease sublimit, that is,
what many insurance companies do is that
if there is a heart disease then we will
give only Rs 2 lakh in it.  If there is liver disease
then we will give only Rs 3 lakh.  So
whenever you take insurance for your parents,
remember that there should not be any room limit
and there should not be any sub-limit for any disease.
Feature number four is no copay.
Friends, what does copay mean is that suppose your
bill comes for Rs 1 lakh, then the insurance company
silently adds a clause that
you will have to pay 20%.  That means you give ₹20,000 and
we will give you ₹80,000.  So whenever you
take insurance, you have to keep in mind that no one should
pay in it.  Pay 100% to the insurance company.
So friends, now let us come to the
two best health insurance plans for parents.
So friends, I have shortlisted two plans here.  The
first plan is
HDFC Airgo's Optimus Secure and the second
is Care Supreme.  And friends, Ditto Insurance has
helped me in shortlisting these plans.
So if we talk about Ditto,
it is not an agent who
calls again and again and harasses you that you
need health insurance.  Take this plan
, you should take that plan.  no way.
He is an unbiased insurance advisor
who compares and provides the best plans for you.  The
rest is your choice as to which one to
take.  Here, everything from documentation to
claim taking is handled for free.  All
you have to do is visit the website
and schedule a call.  That's it.
So friends, to get a trusted health insurance
policy, there is a link in the description, do
check it out.  So friends, now let us come to
our first health insurance plan.  Which
is HDFC Ergo's Optimus Secure Plan.
So friends, if you are looking for premium quality and
trust then this can be the
perfect plan for you.  If we talk about some of its
features, then number one is claim
settlement ratio.  Its claim settlement
ratio is around 98%.
Meaning the claim is almost guaranteed.  Number two, there is
no room rent limit in this.   That
means there is no restriction whether the
room has to be taken for Rs 5,000 or Rs 10,000.  There is
no such restriction.  Number
three secure benefit.  This means that
suppose you have taken an insurance cover of 10 lakhs,
then it will be doubled from the very first day, that is,
you will be given protection of 20 lakhs, that is,
double coverage from day one and
fourth is friends coverage range, that is,
in this plan you get cover of every range,
if you want to take insurance of 5 lakhs or
2 crores, all ranges are available in it and
friends, if we talk about advance, then in this
you get Optima Well Bean,
inside Optima Well Bean, number one
you get free doctor consultations,
number two home sample collection, that is, if you get any test
done, then the sample is taken from home itself.
And number three is 50% discount on
medicines.  That means friends, those who are
looking for premium service along with trust
can check out this plan.  Now let's come to
our plan number two which is Care
Supreme.  Friends, this plan is for those who are
looking for a budget-friendly option along with wellness.
If we talk about its features then it is
number one pocket friendly premium.  That means
it provides a budget friendly premium for all the middle class families.
Number two instead cover add on.
Suppose friends, if your parents have any
chronic problem like BP,
diabetes or diseases like asthma,
then in that case you get a waiting period of only 30 days.
You don't have to wait for a year or two.  Number
three wellness benefit.  Friends, this plan
provides a unique feature that if you
achieve your daily step target,
that is, it does not happen that you walk 5,000 steps,
walk 10,000 steps, then
whenever you will renew this plan next time,
you will get a discount of 30% on it.  And number
four is coverage range.  So friends, within this plan
also you can take a health insurance plan ranging from Rs 5 lakh to Rs 1 crore as per
your budget.  But now the question arises,
which one is the best among these two?  So let's
compare the two.  So friends, now
you can see both the plans on your screen.
HDFC's Optimal Secure Plan
and Care Supreme.  So as you will see, first of all we will
talk about network hospitals.
That means how many hospitals are covered under these plans
?  So friends, as you will see, there are
11,400 hospitals under Care Supreme,
which is quite good.  But HDFC has
13,000 hospitals i.e.
excellent network and hospitals.
Friends, the second feature is the claim
settlement ratio.  That means if they receive 100
claims, how many of them have they
settled?  So as you can see,
if we look at the claim settlement ratio of Care Supreme,
it is 93%.  If we
look at HDFC, it is more than 97%.  That means
in this case also HDFC's plan is much better.  The
next feature is co-payment which
I told you earlier should not happen.
So you will see that there is no copayment in KS Supreme
and also not in HDFC.
That means this is a good feature in both.
Next is room rent, friends, there is
no limit on room rent.  So you will see
that in this also you can take any room
in Care Supreme and you can also take any room in HDFC.
After that, friends,
they have not put a limit on disease sublimit, that is, they have not put a limit on any disease that
only Rs 2 lakh will be given for heart and only Rs 3
lakh for liver.  So you can see that there is
no sub-limit for any disease in both the plans.
After that, friends, there is pre-existing
disease waiting.  That is, if you already have any disease before
taking insurance, then
what is the waiting period for it?  So as you can see
Care Supreme has a waiting period of 3 years.
If you look at HDFC, there
is a waiting period of 3 years in it also.  That means, there
is a slight drawback in both that
for pre-existing you will have to first wait for 3 years.  That's where
pre and post hospitalization
cover comes in, friends.  That means,
you need some care before getting admitted in the hospital and
after hospitalization, so friends,
in Care Supreme you get 60 days of pre-
hospitalization i.e.
before the hospital and 180 days of post-hospitalization.  If you
look at HDFC,
you will get 60 days advance and post
hospitalization 180 days, that is, it is same in both
and quite good.  After that friends, the matter
comes to no claim bonus.  That means, whenever
you do not make a claim in any year,
you are given a bonus in the next renewal.  So as
you will see, in Care Supreme also you are
given 50% per year bonus and
in HDFC also you are given 50%.  Friends, if we
talk about Ayush treatments, then
facilities are available in both, as you might know, there is a
government department of Ayurvedic
medicines.  In that too, both the facilities
are available in both the plans.  After that
friends comes the restoration benefit.  So
friends, this means that suppose
you took a claim in some year.  Like your
insurance was for Rs 10 lakh.  You have
already used Rs 7-8 lakh out of that.  But if in the
same year some other problem arises, some other
disease occurs, then what happens in that case is
that you are left with no money left
to claim.  So friends, this restoration
benefit is very useful there.  That means
in the Care Supreme plan you get unlimited bar
restoration benefit.
Friends, if we talk about SGFC,
your
cover can be restored only once a year.  Friends, the next feature is health
checkups.  So as you will see you do not get
any health checkup free of cost at Care Supreme.
If you look at HDFC,
you get a complete free
health checkup once a year.  However,
you do not get maternity benefits in both the plans.
And if we talk about day care, then
day care facility is available to you in both the plans.  That
means friends, I
compared both the plans in detail
and told you the features of both.
So now friends let us come to the premiums
i.e. how much will you have to pay per year?  So as
you can see on your screen now.
Suppose you have two parents,
one is 62 and the other is 58.  This
also depends on the age.  So your Care Supreme
premium will be around Rs 94542 every year.  Whereas if the age is
51 and 55 then it will cost around Rs 57179.
If it has to be done for only one parent, it will cost
around Rs 40,000.  Friends,
if you look at HDFC, if the age is 62 and 58 then it will cost
around Rs 86,000.  That means
Care is falling short of Supreme.  Whereas if the
age is 51 and 55 then it will cost Rs 60,000.  If you
are single and your age is 55 years then it will cost Rs 44614.  That
means friends, you can
see and compare both the premiums on your screen.
So in the end friends, I would
like to say that we have learnt a lot from our parents.
They have raised us, brought us up
, made us capable.  That too by
forgetting all his needs.  Now that they
need us, can't we give them the best
treatment?  Therefore, health
insurance is not an expense.
This is our responsibility.  So friends, there is a
link to the date in the description.  Schedule a call.
No spam, no pressure.
They will find the
best plan for you as per your requirement and will
also give you unbiased advice.
So now friends, we will meet
in the next such interesting get-infective video.  Till then
do like, share, comment and
subscribe to my YouTube channel Which is
Money Ride.